<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Beilabs.com - Jonathan Clarke's blog</title>
    <description>Beilabs.com - Jonathan Clarke's blog</description>
    <link>http://beilabs.com</link>
    
      <item>
	<title>RubyMotion - It's on my Christmas list</title>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://s3.amazonaws.com/blog.beilabs.com/images/2012-05-08-ruby-motion.png&quot; title=&quot;Welcome to Ruby Motion&quot; alt=&quot;Welcome to Ruby Motion&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rubymotion.com/&quot;&gt;RubyMotion&lt;/a&gt; is a revolutionary toolchain for iOS.  It lets you quickly develop and test native iOS applications for iPhone or iPad, all using the awesome Ruby language you know and love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run your app in the simulator.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deploy on your IOS device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create an App Store package.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Navigate and introspect the iOS API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Behavior-driven development framework&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RubyMotion makes Ruby as fast as Objective-C&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's Ruby stupid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Seriously, what is not to like about this?  BTW, It was built by the original Mac Ruby author, &lt;a href=&quot;http://chopine.be/&quot;&gt;Laurent Sansonetti&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HipByte/RubyMotionSamples&quot;&gt;RubyMotion code samples here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rubymotion.com&quot;&gt;http://rubymotion.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
	<link>http://beilabs.com/2012/05/08/ruby-motion-is-on-my-christmas-list</link>
      </item>
    
      <item>
	<title>The importance of the zone in the workplace</title>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;I love programming, it's rare that a day passes that I don't sit in front of a keyboard to write a few lines of code.  It's my job and my passion.  It requires an immense amount of concentration, often I find myself so involved in the problem in front of me that I block out all other distractions.  That is at least when I have a set of decent headphones.  Today I forgot mine at home and it has been hell!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My office has a variety of other departments, many are on the phone chasing new leads for the next event, others are chatting amongst themselves.  One thing is constant though, the radio.  I hate the radio with a passion.  Filled with advertising, playing music that I have heard day in day out, over and over again.  I've tried to ignore it but it's always cackling in the background playing the one and only station that it can get access to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I'm zoned in I really don't like to be disturbed, when I get sidetracked by a colleague then I lose my focus on the problem and it takes me some time to get back to where I was.  Lately I've been a fan of &lt;a href=&quot;http://di.fm/&quot; title=&quot;Digitally Imported&quot;&gt;Digitally Imported&lt;/a&gt;.  Streaming music that is just ideal for getting me to that point of utmost concentration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/blog.beilabs.com/images/2012-04-02-the-importance-of-the-zone-in-the-workplace.jpg&quot; title=&quot;The importance of the zone in the workplace&quot; alt=&quot;The importance of the zone in the workplace&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's hard to explain the zone, it's a place where I'm devoting 100% of my concentration to a problem.  I often find myself completely detached, fixated on the problem and its various solutions, typing furiously on the keyboard trying to get my thoughts out before they vanish.  It takes time to reach this place, concentration is vital.  Facebook, twitter and email clients are shut off so I'm not being constantly interrupted.  It's my form of meditation, it leaves me completely relaxed and focused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don't attempt to do this all day though, there is a time when exhaustion will set in.  Regular breaks and fresh air is vital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All that said, I really wish there was a new office rule; when I wear my headphones then simply fuck off; let me enjoy the zone for just a little bit longer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
	<link>http://beilabs.com/2012/05/01/headphones-and-the-zone</link>
      </item>
    
      <item>
	<title>30, am I past it?</title>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;It's Anzac day.  It's also my birthday, Australia grinds to a halt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holy crap, I'm suddenly 30.  Well that came along fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friends say it's all downhill for me from now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Old man, past his prime, time to settle down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Screw that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's only the beginning...time to play some two-up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
	<link>http://beilabs.com/2012/04/25/thirty-years-old-am-i-past-it</link>
      </item>
    
      <item>
	<title>Evergreen - Beautiful Javascript unit testing</title>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://s3.amazonaws.com/blog.beilabs.com/images/2012-04-01-jasmine-sample-tests.png&quot; title=&quot;Jasmine testing&quot; alt=&quot;Jasmine Javascript testing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've been coding quite a bit lately after work lately since I got back from Nepal.  While I was introduced to Jasmine a fair while ago I just recently discovered &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jnicklas/evergreen/&quot; title=&quot;Evergreen gem&quot;&gt;evergreen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Evergreen is a tool to run javascript unit tests for client side JavaScript. It combines a server which allows you to serve up and run your specs in a browser, as well as a runner which uses Capybara and any of its drivers to run your specs. Evergreen uses the Jasmine unit testing framework for JavaScript.  I'm a huge fan of automating my tests and you can see if your JS tests pass by running in the console:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;bundle exec rake spec:javascripts&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Handy stuff.  Now back to write some decent, tested Javascript for a change.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
	<link>http://beilabs.com/2012/04/01/evergreen-beautiful-javascript-unit-testing</link>
      </item>
    
      <item>
	<title>Holy smokes I'm hitched</title>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Fantastic news, I got married in March to a wonderful woman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She's incredible on many fronts. Not only can she take my organs and sell them on the black market if we ever end up in financial bother, she can also kick my ass in Words with Friends (Friends often turn to enemies when she plays)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://a5.sphotos.ak.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ak-ash3/p480x480/563677_10151511808790341_513525340_24045851_1192947221_n.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Jonathan &amp;amp; Kisu in the Garden of Dreams, Kathmandu&quot; alt=&quot;Jonathan &amp;amp; Kisu in the Garden of Dreams&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a wonderful traditional Newari ceremony at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newachen.com/&quot; title=&quot;Newa Chen&quot;&gt;Newa Chen&lt;/a&gt;, I really cannot recommend this place enough.  Fantastic lodgings, food, great service and they really rolled out the red carpet for each of our guests. If you're ever in Kathmandu, book rooms way in advance, totally worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent the rest of the 2 weeks filling out visa applications for our Australian permenant residency.  Stress levels were elevated, flights were delayed and nails we're bitten to nubs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We received the good news though at the top of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.raniban.com/&quot; title=&quot;Raniban Retreat&quot;&gt;Raniban Retreat&lt;/a&gt; while watching a spectacular sunrise over Pokhara.  We had the place all to ourselves, not a single other guest for miles around.  Jealous much?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://s3.amazonaws.com/blog.beilabs.com/images/2012-03-09-raniban-retreat.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Jonathan &amp;amp; Kisu at the Raniban Retreat&quot; alt=&quot;Jonathan &amp;amp; Kisu at the Raniban Retreat&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
	<link>http://beilabs.com/2012/03/09/holy-smokes-im-hitched</link>
      </item>
    
      <item>
	<title>Taking stock of 2012</title>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;My nephew Sidney was born!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proposed to a wonderful woman, she said yes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deal Pinch made Techcrunch, CNN, LA Times and many more publications&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Application for Australian Permenant Residency is now underway&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Launched Australian Art Review&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Launched Editorial Management System (major project)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commenced work on the new Westwick-Farrow CMS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commenced work on as yet un-named mobile project, stealth baby yeah!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Launched Deal Pinch Mobile&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2011 has been a busy year.  2012 will bring a wedding in Kathmandu, a trip to Ireland, Australian residency and hopefully even more startup success.  I'll also get to meet Sidney for the very first time high in the mountains!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
	<link>http://beilabs.com/2011/12/31/taking-stock-of-2011</link>
      </item>
    
      <item>
	<title>Thoughts about mentors</title>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;So you've got a mentor?  Couple of pointers and tips for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You're always going to get conflicting advice / opinions depending on who you speak to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite their best intentions, some mentors can get it wrong. mentors are not always right!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An opinion is just that, an opinion.  It's not fact just because it comes out of a mentors mounth, research everything they say and don't take it as a concrete fact just because they believe it is!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choose a mentor that you can work with over a long period of time.  They're often like a co-founder, make sure you get along with them because a good one is worth their weight in gold!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, always know that it's your company! Decide the direction that you want to take it and make sure it is a direction that makes you happy!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
	<link>http://beilabs.com/2011/12/12/thoughts-about-mentors</link>
      </item>
    
      <item>
	<title>Ireland means business</title>
	<description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/Gy6e31wI6Qg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;


&lt;p&gt;We've come a long way since the last recession. While Ireland does not have the natural resources of countries like Australia or the US, we do have a large, skilled, educated workforce; this is Irelands greatest asset&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've always known that Ireland is an awesome country, now you do too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
	<link>http://beilabs.com/2011/12/09/ireland-by-the-numbers</link>
      </item>
    
      <item>
	<title>Work hard. Cry less. And realize you’re part of history.</title>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Another interesting article from Michael Arrington today.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://uncrunched.com/2011/11/27/startups-are-hard-so-work-more-cry-less-and-quit-all-the-whining/&quot;&gt;Startups are hard. So work more, cry less, and quit all the whining&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The article gave a number of examples of people talking about how hard they work.  It's something that everyone does, they work hard, they tell people about it. Woe is my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the article he writes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Work hard. Cry less. And realize you’re part of history.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a great phrase for any startup entrepreneur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Startups are tough, if they weren't then everyone would be doing one.  Competition couldn't be higher, there is always someone ready to copy your latest feature or implement the idea you just had in the shower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Satisfaction is something that everyone craves in their profession.  Depression is something that effects everyone at some point in their lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Write up a list of things that you want to achieve by the end of the day and do it.  If you don't get through them all then you need to take a long look at how you are estimating your time.  Being a better judge of how long something will take comes with experience, the more you get the easier it becomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I often look back at my time in China working for a Chinese software company.  16 hour days were part of the norm.  There was such an abundance of talent, naturally once a developer burned out he was replaced with the next person in line, with another 10 people ready to take their place.  This was the type of place where even after a 16 hour shift you would be expected to be at your cubicle at 8.30am, checked in the system and ready for the days work.  While the pressure was similar to a startup environment it had none of the incentives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time last year I admit that I was depressed. I had thrown myself head first into a hobby &lt;a href=&quot;http://dealpinch.com&quot;&gt;startup&lt;/a&gt; which took up any free time I had on hand.  Often coding up ideas till 4 in the morning only to get up for work at 7am the next day.  As you can expect, burnout came and it came hard.  My relationship with my future wife deteriotated.  I'm glad to say she stuck around and for that I will always be thankful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These days I work on projects in a much more methodical manner.  I question why a certain feature is needed much more often.  I take each day as it comes with a goal to be performed every single day.  Win small, win often and above all ship regularly.  Your health and satisfaction will improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While being a part of history is great, make sure that enjoy your life.  You only get one.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
	<link>http://beilabs.com/2011/11/28/work-hard-cry-less-be-part-of-history</link>
      </item>
    
      <item>
	<title>Bootstrap Xtra released</title>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Bootstrap Xtra extends Bootstrap
Bootstrap is a toolkit from Twitter designed to kickstart development of webapps and sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It includes base CSS and HTML for typography, forms, buttons, tables, grids, navigation, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bootstrap Xtra inludes extra features that are not included in Bootstrap but may be useful for some people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can grab it here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://lightglitch.github.com/bootstrap-xtra/&quot;&gt;http://lightglitch.github.com/bootstrap-xtra/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
	<link>http://beilabs.com/2011/11/27/bootstrap-xtra</link>
      </item>
    
      <item>
	<title>Get 'er done...</title>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;I had that idea years before they did it.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's a common statement amongst developers.  The problem is that they either failed to execute or just never acted up on the idea in the first place.  Working alone can be a very daunting task.  A sole developer can cut a very lonely figure and often as a result failed startups are a dime a dozen.  My advice: just fucking do it.  Words to live by though often words words to regret.  Work on your idea one line of code at a time, one meeting at a time, one night at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Missed opportunities happen all the time and will always continue to occur.  Get out and meet like minded people at networking events like Ruby Oceania and Silicon Beach in Sydney.  One of my resolutions this year is to be much more open for opportunities of any description.  Saying yes to new chances, meeting new people and working on new ideas.  Follow up with chance encounters, you never know what path it will lead you down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make 2011 your year to shine because no-one else is ever going to make it for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
	<link>http://beilabs.com/2011/01/03/get-er-done</link>
      </item>
    
      <item>
	<title>Programming is difficult...</title>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jamesjohnsona.tumblr.com/post/2088297700/programming-has-been-difficult&quot;&gt;James Johnson&lt;/a&gt; wrote earlier this month that &quot;Programming has been difficult...(But Rewarding).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mastering programming takes an enormous amount of time.  Like any discipline it requires dedication and hard work to become well regarded in the field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn something new today, repeat what you learned and repeat it again.  Chances are that the next time you do it will be significantly faster than the first time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Always be willing to try new languages and approaches, it will serve you well.  Banging your head off a wall for hours just to get it to finally do what you want is the reward that all developers crave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Programming is difficult, depending on what you want to accomplish, but the rewards are so satisfying that I can't see myself in any other profession.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
	<link>http://beilabs.com/2010/12/29/programming-is-difficult</link>
      </item>
    
      <item>
	<title>Messing around with the Ruby IMAP and Mail libraries</title>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;So today I got to build a small little application that does the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;   It reads a specific email account through the IMAP protocol&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;   Imports the message and all of it's attachments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;   Saves the message to a postgres database&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;   Marks the message as read&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;   Copies the message to the Complete folder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;   Removes the message from the Inbox&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;So why did I do this? Well, I really want a simple way to post messages from my phone to my blog.  Gmail currently allows me to work on drafts while on the move and will push when I resume connectivity.  Hopefully this will result in a vast increase in the number of posts I make in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this was down to the Ruby IMAP library and Mikel Lindsaars awesome Mail library.  You can view the source code of this website at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/beilabs/www.beilabs.com&quot;&gt;https://github.com/beilabs/www.beilabs.com&lt;/a&gt; *This blog is now replaced with a simplified Jekyll blog framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are still a number of things to do such as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;   Read and process attachments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;   Save to Amazon S3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
	<link>http://beilabs.com/2010/12/28/messing-around-with-the-ruby-imap-and-mail-libraries</link>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
